MAHIMA RAO

619-630-7421 | mahiima.rao@gmail.com | Los Angeles, California | PORTFOLIO | LINKEDIN | GITHUB

SUMMARY

I'm a full stack developer proficient in React, Node JS, Express Javascript, HTML, and CSS. Before this, I worked with as an urban designer iterating through a design idea to revitalize a river side low-income zone. I have worked with city of Phoenix to integrate and improve public transportation. I'm currently working on building a React app which facilitates easy resume writing.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

MERN stack [MongoDB, Express, React Node JS], HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Ruby on Rails, SQL, APIs(Google maps, Open weather), Adobe suite, CAD, Sketchup

PROJECTS

Résumé writer

Users can choose between 4 pre-designed templates to write a résumé without the worry of indentations and font sizes.

Technologies used: MongoDB, Express, React, Node JS, Javascript, HTML, CSS, Semantic-react, Heroku

Vacation Finder

This app was built by a team of developers. It is a crowdsourced image platform which allows you to login and add or search for locations that you might be interested in visiting. It also comes with location on map and weather details.

Technologies used: MongoDB, Express, Node JS, Javascript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Heroku, MLab.

The Cookbook

The focus of this project was to give users a platform to share their recipes. The app was built entirely using Ruby on Rails implementing full CRUD with authentication for password protection.

Technologies used: Ruby on rails version (Ruby 2.5.0, Rails 5.1.5), Postgresql, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, Heroku

Remastering Space Invaders

The entire game is written in HTML and designed with CSS and animated in JavaScript using jQuery. **Technologies used:** Javascript, Jquery, HTML, CSS, Adobe Photoshop CS6

EXPERIENCE

ASIA INITIATIVES, Urban Design Researcher

Jan 2014 to Jun 2016

- Developed urban design proposals for restoration of Vaigai River in Madurai, India.
- Helped design the SoCCs (Social Capital Credits) system to incentivize riverside communities to become custodians of the river and earn healthcare, education and skill empowerment in turn.

PHOENIX URBAN RESEARCH LAB, AZ, Project Manager

Jan 2012 to Apr 2012

- Authored a historic mapping system for downtown Phoenix.

EDUCATION

General Assembly Web Development Immersive

Jan 2018 to Apr 2018

Arizona State University Master of Urban Design

Aug 2010 to May 2012

Sushant School of Architecture, India **Bachelor of Architecture** 2007

July 2002 to May